<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andrew Watts&#39;s Blog</title>
    <description>Andrew Watts&#39;s blog for his work and hobbies, especially learning to play music (guitar, bass guitar, and cello primarily), music theory, programming, and running.
</description>
    <link>https://awatts.us/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://awatts.us/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 16:53:22 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 16:53:22 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My 20th Linuxversary</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I can’t remember the exact date that I started using Linux, but it’s been 20 years
sometime in early January. With some Christmas ‘95 money I bought a book at MediaPlay
that came with Slackware 2.3 (released 1995-05-10) on CD. The Wikipedia entry for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slackware&quot;&gt;Slackware&lt;/a&gt; claims 3.0 was the first version
to come on CD, but my bookshelf disagrees, and the book the CD came with was written
by Patrick Volkerding himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time I had my first computer of my own, which had a Cyrix Cx486DX2-80, 8MB RAM,
and a decent sized hard drive for the time; I’m thinking it was either 500MB or maybe
even 1GB. It came with DOS 6.22 and Windows 3.11 For Workgroups. I didn’t have the
Microsoft install media (and I wouldn’t be surprised if the store I bought it from
didn’t have a valid license), so I feared formatting and used UMSDOS and Loadlin
to install and boot Linux on top of DOS and the FAT filesystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my next computer I moved on to SuSE, which I stuck with through the 6.x and 7.x
versions. I took a couple year detour through BeOS, FreeBSD, and OpenBSD before
landing on Debian around 2004 with Woody (3.0). Eventually I got sick of how bad
Linux was on laptops (I’ve gathered it’s improved immensely) and bought a PowerBook
G4 with MacOS X 10.3 (Unix on a laptop that works!) and have had a couple more Mac
desktops and laptops over the years (typing this on a 2012 MacBook Pro 15”), but
I’ve kept some sort of Debian box at work and/or home constantly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 15:37:14 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://awatts.us/2016/01/01/my-20th-linuxversary.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://awatts.us/2016/01/01/my-20th-linuxversary.html</guid>
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Starting From Scratch With Octopress 3.0</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The first version of this post was written in February of 2015. It’s finally going
to go up on December 31st. I’ve been busy and Octopress 3.x is still not entirely
kink free (in fact, I had to run&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;bundle &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;exec &lt;/span&gt;octopress new post &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Starting From Scratch With Octopress 3.0&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;because for some reason&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-bash&quot; data-lang=&quot;bash&quot;&gt;octopress new post ...&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;alone causes a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;LoadError&lt;/code&gt; on
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;octopress-genesis-theme&lt;/code&gt;) and still doesn’t work with Jekyll 3.x.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long ago I tried starting a blog on GitHub with Octopress 2.x, but I quickly got
frustrated with it because it involved basically forking Brandon Mathis’s blog and
tweaking it and hoping nothing upstream conflicted with any changes you made, which
it always did. Or at least for me, but I could’ve been doing everything wrong. So
I’m just blowing that version of the blog away and starting over now that Octopress
is a set of Ruby gems instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’ve figured out how to get Octopress 3.x working I’m going to try to
seriously get this blog going. Out of the gate I’m using the default &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/octopress/genesis-theme&quot;&gt;Genesis theme&lt;/a&gt;, because &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/octopress/ink&quot;&gt;Ink&lt;/a&gt;
isn’t documented well enough yet for other themes to exist or for me
to take a stab at it myself (at least given that I don’t have a lot of time to
spend on it). I’m also planning to add Disqus comments in the not too distant future,
once I’m happy with the things are working. I’ll also slowly remove all the default
boilerplate Jekyll stuff and personalize it. But I want to get this officially
started before the end of 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming soon: a post about who I am and what this blog will be about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 13:53:20 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://awatts.us/administrative/2015/12/31/starting-from-scratch-with-octopress-3-0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://awatts.us/administrative/2015/12/31/starting-from-scratch-with-octopress-3-0.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>administrative</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
